This time, we're going
with my strategy.
Help me out.
Mother...
These two are quite annoying.
Why don't you split them up...
(サスケ)今度は俺の作戦でいく。
協力しろ。
and take them on separately?
(ゼツ)母さん
こいつら やっかいだね。
もうさ こいつら分けちまえば？
そして １匹ずつ…。
Sasuke!
Now you won't be able
to seal Mother away...
First, I'll suck out all of your chakra!
うっ！
(ナルト)サスケ！
Damn it!
(ゼツ)これで
もう母さんを封印できない。
まずは お前のチャクラを
すべて吸い尽くす。
クソッ！
aimaina hyouden koshiraete hitatteru no
I create a vague critical biography and wallow in it
seisei saisai nani o mada matteru no
Generation after generation, time after time,
what are you still waiting for
itsunomanika hitori ni natta
I was all alone before I knew it
tameiki hitotsu haite nageite
Breathed out a single sigh and lamented
jounetsu moyashita ano koro o
Those days of burning passion
shinketsu sosoide torimodosunda
Put your heart and soul into getting them back
en de tsunagareba kono hibi mo
Bind these days with bonds and perhaps
suteru hodo koware tenaidarou
They can be salvaged
ayumi o tomenaide
Don't stop walking forward
kibou o sutenaide
Don't give up hope
douka furimuite
Please look back
dou ka kimiyo
Please, if you would
jin jin kokoro ga itamunara
If the heart throbs with pain
kannen no ori o uchiyaburu nda
Break through the ideology that imprisons you
enen tsukihi wa megurukedo
Time goes around for eternity
suteru ni wa yami ga asaidarou
But the darkness within you is still shallow,
not worth throwing it all away
jounetsu moyashita ano koro o
Those days of burning passion
shinketsu sosoide torimodosu nda
Put your heart and soul into getting them back
ai o wakeaeba kono hibi mo
If we love each other then surely these days will
mouichido kimi o terasudarou
Once again, shine upon you
Connecting Thoughts
It's hard to believe.
So both your powers and Sasuke's
are necessary in order
to seal away this Kaguya?
Yeah! But like I said earlier,
I can't sense Sasuke at all!
(オビト)信じられんが→
とにかく
そのカグヤってのを封印するには→
The ice... is moving.
ナルトとサスケの
２人の力が必要ってことだな。
あぁ でも さっきも言ったけど
サスケが感知できねえんだ。
Over there!
(カカシ)氷が 動いてるな。
あそこだ！
She's merged with Nature!
くっ…。
《自然と一体化してやがる！》
Naruto!
She's finally showing herself.
かはっ！
You said you suddenly stopped
sensing Sasuke?
(サクラ)ナルト！
Yeah.
Then I suspect he was taken
to another dimension.
やっと出てきやがったな。
サスケは急に感知できなくなった
と言ったな。
If I resonate my Kamui
the next time she connects
and opens a portal
to another Time-Space,
あぁ。
なら 別空間へ飛ばされたと
想像できる。
I'm positive I can enter it.
もう一度 やつが空間をつなげ→
If Sasuke is there, I can bring
him back to this dimension.
開いたと同時
俺の神威と共鳴させれば→
However...
I'll need an enormous amount
of chakra to do it,
まず間違いなく入り込める。
since it's not my own Time-Space.
そこに サスケがいれば→
If my chakra runs out
while I'm there, I'm done.
こっちに
連れて帰ってくることはできる。
ただ…
それには膨大なチャクラがいる。
Then I'll go with you.
The real me won't go down
that quickly.
俺の時空間じゃないからな。
Because I'm strong.
Your Clone Chakra isn't enough.
向こうでチャクラが切れたら終わりだ。
なら 俺も行く。
Would it still be inadequate
with my 100 Healings Chakra?
本体も
すぐにやられたりはしねえ。
俺は 強えから。
That would give me
the bare minimum.
分身の お前のチャクラでも足りない。
Both of you, come with me.
All right!
(サクラ)私の百豪のチャクラがあっても→
I'm not going to waste time
on a speech,
足りませんか？
because I'm almost out of time.
それで 限度いっぱいだ。
But...
I just ask that you let me
walk in front of you...
２人とも俺と来い。
はい。
(オビト)時間のない俺が→
今更 詭弁をたれるつもりはない。
and die for you.
ただ
せめて お前たちの前を歩いて…。
Then it's true.
This man can't be saved.
死なせてくれ。
That's why he intends to die...
《やっぱりそうだ。
この人 もう助からないんだ。
We don't even know if Sasuke
is in that Time-Space.
But we'll start by getting
into close range with her.
だから 死ぬ気で…》
I promise to find Sasuke,
and deliver him to the real you.
サスケが その空間にいるかどうかも
わからない。
だが まずは やつの懐に入り→
Obito.
Thanks for rescuing me...
サスケは必ず俺が見つけ
お前の本体まで届ける。
And Sasuke too.
オビト 俺のことを助けてくれて
ありがとう。
Don't thank someone like me.
Just keep an eye on the enemy.
そして サスケまで…。
こんな俺に礼など言うな。
So no more masks, huh?
敵を見てろ。
I'm Kakashi's friend,
your father's subordinate,
もう 面はねえんだな。
I'm an Uchiha just
like Sasuke,
and...
俺は カカシの友であり→
The Hokage is someone
who endures pain
and takes the lead in
front of everyone.
お前の父の部下であり→
サスケと同じ うちはであり
そして…。
The way he forges ahead
draws others towards him.
((火影ってのは
痛えのを我慢して→
He makes you want to reach out
when he's about to stumble.
みんなの前を
歩いてるやつのことだ。
I was your senior who dreamt
the same dream as you.
そして あいつの そういう
歩き方が仲間を引き寄せる。
(つまずきそうなら助けたくなる))
Naruto!
And you said
your name was Sakura?
俺は… お前と同じ夢を見た
先輩だった。
Keep a hand on me,
so we can teleport to a different
Time-Space at any moment.
ナルト そして サクラと言ったな。
Got it.
俺の体に触れておけ。
いつでも別空間へ飛べるように。
(サクラ)はい。
She knows about us, after all.
We have to keep in mind
that even if we jump into
her dimension with Kamui,
she'll perceive us.
俺たちのこと バレてるな やっぱ。
So we're not worth her attention, eh?
神威でやつの空間へ
飛んだとしても→
感知されることを
考慮しておかないとな。
Yeah, come over here.
What you want...
is my chakra, right?!
《こちらは
気にもとめないってことか》
Whatever jutsu I use,
she's just going to absorb it.
《そう こっちへ来い。
お前の狙いは 俺のチャクラだろ。
So what will work best
on her is also...
バカでけえ術しても
吸収されちゃ意味ねえ。
a feint and taijutsu!
I can't use a pervy move
to distract her anymore.
やっぱ こいつにも
いちばん効くのは陽動と体術だ。
So I gotta go back to the basics
and corner her!
If she tries to escape through
that weird window again,
出オチのおいろけ系は
もう陽動には使えねえ。
I'll enter it with her.
俺の基本に立ち返ってやるんだ。
That's where I'll look for Sasuke!
Even now, I can sense
Sasuke's chakra clearly!
それで追い込む。
こいつがまた あの変な扉から
逃げようとしたときに→
This is my Time-Space.
一緒に入る。
You are powerless here.
そこで サスケを捜す。
今でもサスケのチャクラは
はっきり感じてんだ！》
Are you ready, Naruto?
Yeah!
I'm going to boost your chakra
to the boiling point!
(カグヤ)ここは わらわの空間だ。
お前は何もできぬ。
Vapor Style: Unrivalled Strength!
(穆王)準備はできたな ナルト。
おう！
一気にチャクラを
沸点までもっていくぞ。
怪力無双！
All right!
うぉ～！
A-Amazing...
I infused chakra for you, Naruto!
よっしゃ！
す すごい。
Thank you, Kurama!
Multi Shadow Clone Jutsu!
(九喇嘛)チャクラは
練っておいてやったぞ ナルト。
サンキュー 九喇嘛。
多重 影分身の術。
Right now,
this place is my Time-Space!
U...
zu...
ma...
今 ここは
俺の空間だってばよ！
ki!
Naruto
Uzumaki
うっ！
ずっ！
Barrage!
まっ！
きっ！
It opened!
ナルト一帯連弾！
The real me will go!
《開いたな。
本体の俺が行く》
He forced his way in?
Impossible!
ん!? 入り込めたのか？
He disappeared?
バカな！
Looks like several managed
to get in.
The other two ran out of power
and faded.
《ん!? 消えた？》
Seems your clones didn't
have enough chakra.
(ゼツ)何匹か
入り込んでしまったようだな…。
Are you the original Naruto?
他の２匹は力尽きて 消えたか。
So what if I am?
分身では
チャクラが もたなかったようだな。
Mother, he's made it all the way
into this Root Time-Space.
お前が オリジナルか？
It's not good that
he's here in this place
なら どうだってんだ!?
that connects directly
to the other five Time-Spaces.
《ゼツ : 母さん…。
こいつ この始球空間まで
入り込んできてる。
He might be able to get
to where Sasuke is,
using the resonance of
the dual opposite powers.
他の５つの空間へ
直接 つながる ここに→
Take that weird jutsu earlier,
こいつがいるのは まずいよ。
this shinobi Naruto has
always been unpredictable.
陰陽の力の共鳴で
サスケのところへ行かれかねない。
We ought to just...
さっきの変な術にしろ→
kill him right now!
このナルトという忍 昔から
何をするか わからない。
We can't do that.
I must absorb
those children's chakra.
こいつは ここで
きっちり 殺しておくべきだ》
You use a huge amount of chakra
whenever you change
the Time-Space of the world, Mother.
それは ダメよ。
あの子たちのチャクラは
吸収しなくては。
You need to preserve the chakra
you've got for an emergency.
《母さんが
世界の空間を変換するとき→
It's better if you don't keep
engaging him.
多くのチャクラを使う。
If you get sealed away,
all will be for naught.
今のチャクラは もしものときに
備えておく必要もある。
No doubt,
you'll lose a lot of chakra.
これ以上 こいつとのやりとりを
のばさないほうがいい。
But you don't need his!
It's better than having our long-
cherished plans turn to dust.
もし 封印されれば 元も子もない。
確かに 多くのチャクラを
失うことになるが→
You're right.
こいつの分は もう いらない。
この長年の計画が
水の泡になるよりは ましだ》
We can kill him with this!
Murderous Bone Ash!
(カグヤ)そうね。
Die!
《ゼツ : これで 殺せる。
共殺しの灰骨》
(ゼツ)死ね！
Now all of his clones
in the Ice World
should be gone as well!
(ゼツ)これで 氷世界の分身も
すべて 消えたはずだ。
Thanks to Naruto,
we were able to successfully hide
inside my Time-Space.
But he's gone, even as a clone.
You're the only one
I can rely on, Sakura.
(オビト)ナルトのおかげで うまく
俺の時空間へ隠れられたが→
I know!
分身でも もう ナルトはいない。
There's a reason
I put myself at the front!
お前だけが頼りだ サクラ。
And I'll do even more than Naruto!
(サクラ)わかってます。
私だって 先頭を
走ってるつもりでいるんです。
こうなったら
ナルト以上に結果を出しますよ。
He's the fool who fell
in love with me...
I'm the one who made
Naruto suffer the most.
I was always wrong,
I always made mistakes.
((私なんかを好きになってくれた
バカだから。
ナルトを いちばん苦しめてたのは
私だった。
I don't want to be wrong
ever again.
I don't want to make
a mistake ever again.
私は いつも 間違ってばかり。
失敗ばかり。
That's why...
I'll never retreat!
もう間違いたくない。
もう失敗したくない。
Leave it to me, Sakura!
I'm the super elite ninja,
and future Hokage, Naruto Uzumaki!
(だから もう引かない！))
Remember my name!
I'm going to become Hokage
((俺に任せてくれ サクラちゃん。
and surpass everyone
who came before me!
いずれ 火影の名を名乗る
超エリート忍者 うずまきナルトという！
Your previously ridiculous dreams
no longer seem silly.
覚えとけ！
俺ってば 火影になって→
I won't let you die!
I simply won't let you!
(どの先代も
超えてやるんだってばよ！))
((かつてのあんたの バカげた夢は
今は もう…。
You're not going to die,
no matter what!
いかせない… いかせてたまるか！
(絶対に
死なせるわけにはいかないのよ))
Looks like we succeeded
in getting in, Obito.
Now that you've teleported
over there,
please don't get crushed
on the other side!
こっちが
うまく入れたようだね オビト。
《飛んだ先で いきなり
やられるなんてことは→
勘弁してくれよ》
We killed the original!
So why aren't they gone?
(ゼツ)オリジナルは殺した
なぜ消えていない？
The real me will go!
Damn it!
Are you okay, Naruto?
《本体の俺がいく》
How is this okay?!
Never mind. Just be ready
when Kaguya comes back.
クソッ！
大丈夫だ ナルト。
これの どこが
大丈夫なんだってばよ。
いいから お前は カグヤが
戻ってきたときに備えていろ！
The Kamui worked.
They're onto us!
I'll draw their attention,
so you two go hide
in the meantime!
I've marked this spot,
神威はうまくいった。
so I can hide in my Time-Space
for the time being.
気づかれた。
You too, Sakura!
俺がやつの注意を
引きつけるから→
その間に
２人は すぐ隠れてくれ。
The other two ran out
of power and faded.
この場所はマーキングできた。
いったん 俺の時空間へ身を隠す。
Seems your clones didn't
have enough chakra.
サクラ お前もだ。
えっ？ あっ…。
Are you the original Naruto?
他の２匹は力尽きて消えたか。
So what if I am?!
分身では チャクラが
もたなかったようだな。
お前がオリジナルか。
So they were just
clones back there.
なら どうだってんだ？
You fooled us.
You got me.
I'm...
the original.
向こうは すべて
ただの分身だったか 騙された。
I've gotta fight smart
and keep them busy
ヘヘ バレちまったか。
so they don't go back over there.
本当は俺がオリジナルだ。
《こいつが向こうに
行かねえように→
This Time-Space should be
connected to the others.
うまく 戦わねえと》
We'll open them one by one
and look for Sasuke.
Right!
この空間から
他の空間につながるはずだ。
一つひとつ開いて サスケを捜し出す。
はい。
I'll give him all the chakra I've got!
ハーッ！
《ありったけのチャクラを この人に》
What an incredibly vast Time-Space...
To be able to connect them
in an instant.
Just who is this Kaguya?!
とんでもなく遠い空間だ。
Isn't that where we were before?
《これを一瞬でつなげるカグヤとは→
I can't sense Sasuke in there!
いったい 何者だ？》
(サクラ)これって前にいた場所。
Are you all right?
ここは サスケを感知できない。
On to the next!
Yes!
ハァ ハァ…。
大丈夫ですか？
次だ。
はい。
I thought it was around here...
What is... that?
この辺りだと思ったがな。
He's not here either.
ここ 何？
ここでもない。
You should rest a bit.
うっ…。
What about chakra?
Oh... I still have reserves.
Keep enough to get back.
少し休んだほうが。
If worse comes to worst
and we can't find Sasuke...
チャクラは？
蓄えは まだあります。
We'll find him!
戻る分は残しておけよ。
Next!
最悪 サスケが
見つからなかった場合は。
見つけます！
次だ。
Be careful about making
a gateway, Mother.
Naruto will get closer to Sasuke.
うわ～。
Plus, I've figured out something.
うかつに入り口を
作らないほうがいいよ 母さん。
The original Naruto has
Truthseeker Orbs around him!
ナルトが サスケに近づく。
それに１つわかったんだけど
ナルトのオリジナルには→
求道玉がついてる。
A sea of acid!
あ！
Are you okay?
酸の海か。
I'm fine!
This is nothing.
You are a Medical Ninja,
aren't you?
大丈夫か!?
大丈夫です このくらい…。
I'll wait until you heal your wound.
That place wasn't
the right one either.
After we rest a little, we'll...
お前は医療忍者だろ？
傷を治すまで待つ。
Don't worry about it!
There's a limit to our chakra, right?
さっきのところも違ったな。
少し休んでから…。
Why don't you tend to
your wound?
そんなのいいです。
Just a little will...
I don't want to waste this chance
that Naruto gave us!
チャクラは限られているでしょ。
なぜ傷を治さない？
少しでも…。
You want to help him
if he starts to stumble, eh?
ナルトがくれたチャンスを
潰すわけにはいかないもの！
Huh?
It's nothing.
Okay, next!
Yes!
つまずきそうなら
助けたくなる …か。
え？
いや。
さあ次だ。
はい！
He's here!
Sasuke!
Over here! Hurry!
Damn it!
ここか！
サスケ君！
サスケ君 こっち！
早く…。
《くっ まずい…》
Sasuke!
Shannaro!
《サスケ君》
うお～！
しゃ～んなろ～！
No way...
How did you do it?
It's one of my abilities.
I can shift myself between spaces,
うう！
although only over a finite distance.
サスケ君！
But I made it here,
thanks to that.
うう！ ハア ハア…。
《そんな…》
boku ni wa wakaru nda uso o tsuite iru kimi ga
I can tell when you're lying
naite ii yo koko ni zutto irukara
It's okay to cry because I'll always be here
sekaijuu ni koborete iru hontou no ai no kimochi
Feelings of true love spills out throughout the world
sagashidashite miushinatte yoake ga kuru no matteru
We search for it but lose it, while waiting for daybreak
migi no hoshi ni wa boku no namae o tsukete
The star on the right will bear my name
kimi ga yonde okureyo
Will you call out to it?
hidari no hoshi ni wa kimi no namae ga ne
The star on the left will bear your name
niau yo zutto soba ni irukara
It's perfect, because we'll always be together
Am I powerless to do
anything but watch?
Right about now, Sakura
and Obito are battling...
I really couldn't do much
for you as your teacher.
Nor Obito and Rin,
as your friend.
どうやって？
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
“The Two of Them... Always”
これが 俺の能力だ。
I just put on airs...
and kept making mistakes.
俺と 離れた空間を
一瞬で入れ替える。
その距離は一定で
決まっているが。
おかげで届いた。